# MYLES GRAY

#### **PROFILE**

I have considerable experience designing, operating and supporting enterprise IT solutions, from both customer and service provider sides.

Strong public speaker, very natural to talk and give seminars in front of groups - formally and informally - and I interact very well with individuals.

I have a very strong interest in new technologies, from virtualisation and sdn to home automation - particularly focused on the VMware SDDC stack for virtualisation, networking and storage, but not limited to it.

My technical experience coupled with my solution design experience help me relate business requirements to technical and design decisions to deliver as best as is possible for every case.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## BLOGGER, BLAH, CLOUD - 03/2012 - PRESENT

I write articles on challenges I face, solutions I find and interesting design/implementation problems I come across on my personal site: <a href="https://blah.cloud">https://blah.cloud</a>

## NOVOSCO, INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER - 08/2014 - PRESENT

I work in the Hosted Platforms division, a small team where we stand up, operationalise and handover dedicated infrastructures and cloud platforms for our MSP customers.

Scripting, automation, through PowerShell and PowerCLI all part of the gig.

Work daily with EMC SANs, Cisco IOS and Nexus switching, blade chassis and whole VMware SDDC suite (NSX, vCD, ESXi, vCenter, VSAN).

Responsible for Novosco "STC" (Single Tenant Cloud) - A new scale-out bare metal IaaS platform - design, implementation, operational handovers and financial modelling under my remit.

# EXITEX LTD, NETWORK & VIRTUALISATION ADMIN - 05/2012 - 08/2014

Responsible for mission critical networking and virtualisation infrastructure redesign, backup/redundancy system design.

Expansion solutions implemented including microwave links for remote premises, site-to-site VPNs and a move from single subnet/VLAN per-site to fully routed core/edge network.

Created documentation wiki for network layouts, iSCSI MPIO failover, software configuration layers and large networking and server relocation and configuration.

## **EDUCATION**

QUEEN'S UNIVERSITY BELFAST - BSC , BUSINESS I.T - 2013

Graduated on a 2-1 with Honours, Awarded best final year project in Technology and Business field by PwC.

ABBEY GRAMMAR SCHOOL - 2009

A-Levels - Physics - A, Technology and Design (Systems and Control) - A, Mathematics - B

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

**VMWARE** 

VCIX6-NV, VCAP6-NV Deploy, VCAP6-DCV Deploy, VCP6-NV, VCP6-DCV, VCP5-DCV

CISCO

CCNA R&S, CCENT R&S

OTHER

Zerto ZCP, PernixPrime

#### **AWARDS**

VMware vExpert, VMware vExpert VSAN, VMware vExpert NSX, PernixPro, Nutanix NTC

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Blah, Cloud - Blog: https://blah.cloud

vSphere Pocket Designbook v3 - Book - PernixData Press:

https://blah.cloud/personal/vsphere-design-pocketbook-v3-available/

# **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Climbing is a huge passion of mine, it leads me to many new places, countries and allows me to meet some amazing people and indulge in my other favourite hobby - photography and videography, examples of both can be found on my site: <a href="https://blah.cloud">https://blah.cloud</a>

#### **REFERENCES**

James Montgomery - Novosco Ltd, HSP Service Delivery Manager - <u>james.montgomery@novosco.com</u>

Adrian Gray - Exitex, Director - adrian.gray@exitex.co.uk